so if you live on planet Earth,
and you are one of seven billion people
that eats food every day.
I need you to pay attention,
because over the next three decades.
We all need to address
one of the most critical
global challenges of our generation.
and I'm not talking
about climate change.
I'm talking about food
and agriculture.
in two thousand and fifty,
our global population
is projected
to reach nine point eight billion,
with sixty, eight percent of us
living in urban city centers
in order to feed
this massive population,
we will need to increase
our agricultural output
by seventy percent
over current levels.
just to put this number in a perspective,
we will need to grow more food
in the next thirty,
five to forty years, then
the previous ten thousand years combined.
put put, simply not only
as our global population becoming bigger,
but but it is also getting denser,
and and we will need to grow
significantly more food
using significantly less landing resources.
complicating our current efforts
to address these major demographic shifts
are the challenges facing
the agricultural industry today.
globally, one third of all the food
that we produce is wasted
according to one point
six billion tons of food
that spoiled on the way to the market,
or expired in a refrigerators,
or were simply thrown out
by supermarkets and restaurants
at the end of the day,
every single year, up to six hundred million people
will get sick eating contaminated food,
highlighting the challenge
that we have of maintaining global food safety.
and maybe unsurprisingly,
the agricultural industry is the single largest
consumer of freshwater,
accounting for seventy percent
of global usage.
Now you will be relieved to know
that the agricultural industry
and that the global movement by universities,
companies and Ngos,
is putting together comprehensive research
and developing novel technology
to address all of these issues.
and many have been doing it
for decades.
but one of the more recent innovations
in food production being deployed
in industrial parks in North America,
in the urban city centers of Asia.
and even in the arid deserts
of the Middle East is controlled.
environment, agriculture,
controlled environment.
agriculture is actually just a fancy way of saying
whether or climate proof farming
and many of these farms
grow food three dimensionally in vertical racks,
as opposed to the two dimensions
of conventional farms.
and so this type of food production
is also referred to as indoor vertical farming.
I've been involved in the indoor
vertical farming space
for the past five and a half years.
Developing technology to make
this type of food production
more efficient and affordable.
this picture was taken outside of a decommissioned shipping container
that we converted into an indoor farm
and then launched into the heart
and the heat of Dubai.
indoor vertical farming
is a relatively recent phenomenon.
commercially speaking.
and the reason for this is
that consumers care more about food safety
and where their food comes from,
and also the necessary technology
to make this possible
is more readily available and lower cost,
and the overall cost
of food production globally
is actually increasing,
making this type of food production
more competitive.
so if you want to build
an indoor vertical farm.
you will need to replace some
of the conventional elements
of farming with artificial substitutes,
starting with sunlight.
in indoor vertical farms,
natural sunlight is replaced
with artificial lighting like Leds.
while there are many different
types of Leds being used.
the one that we decided to install here
is called full spectrum Leds,
which was optimized
for the type of vegetables
that we were growing also
also in order to maximize production
for a given space.
indoor vertical farms also utilize
and install racking systems
to grow vegetables vertically.
and and some of the biggest facilities
stack their production.
fourteen to sixteen
floors high.
now, now now most of these
farms are hydroponic
or aeroplanic systems,
which means that instead of using soil,
they use a substitute material
like polyurethane sponges,
biodegradable biodegradable Peat,
mosque and even use
inorganic materials like per light
and clay pellets.
another another another unique aspect
about these farms
is that they use
a precise nutrient formula
that is circulated and recycled
throughout the facility.
and and this has pumped
directly to the vegetable's root zone
to promote paint growth and and,
and lastly these farms use a sophisticated
monitoring and automation system
to significantly increase productivity,
efficiency and consistency.
and these tools also provide the added benefit
of producing food that is
more traceable and safe.
some of the obvious benefits
of growing food in this way
is that you have year round vestibule production.
you have consistent quality
and your predictable output.
some of the other major benefits
include significant resource
use efficiencies.
particularly water.
for every kilogram of vegetables
grown in this way,
hundreds of leaders of water is conserved
compared to conventional farming methods.
and with the water savings come similar
savings in the use of fertilizer.
one of the highest yielding farms
grows over three hundred
and fifty times more food
per square meter
than a conventional farm.
and weather proofing means
complete control of incoming
contaminants and pests completely eliminated.
the need for the use
of chemical pesticides.
and not to be mistaken, these farms
can produce enormous amounts of food,
with one of the biggest facilities
producing thirty thousand heads
of vegetables a day.
however, as with any new
technology or innovation.
there are some drawbacks,
as you would imagine, growing food
in this way can be incredibly
energy intense.
also, these farms can only produce
a small variety of vegetables commercially,
and the overall cost of the production
still is quite high.
and in order to address these issues,
some of the biggest and most sophisticated farms
are making significant investments,
starting with energy efficiency.
in order to reduce
the high energy usage.
there are efforts to develop
higher efficiency Leds
to develop lasers optimized
for plant growth.
and using even fiber optic cables
like these to channel sunlight
directly into an indoor vertical farm
during the day to reduce
the need for artificial lighting,
also also to reduce the labor costs
associated with harring,
a more sophisticated, more urban,
and also a more high
skilled labor force.
robotics and automation is used extensively
in large scale facilities.
and you can never really
be too resource efficient.
building indoor vertical farms in
and around urban city centers
can help to shorten the agricultural supply chain
and also help to maintain
the nutritional content in vegetables.
also, there are food deserts
in many countries
that have little to no access
to nutritious vegetables.
and as this industry matures,
it will become possible to provide
more equitable access
to high quality, highly nutritious festivals
in even the most underprivileged
of communities.
and finally, and this is really exciting
for me personally.
indoor vertical farming
can actually be integrated seamlessly
into the citiescape to help
repurpose idle, underutilized
and unused urban infrastructure.
in fact, this is already
happening today.
ride ride sharing services have taken
hundreds of thousands of cars off the road,
and and they have significantly reduced
the need for parking.
this is a farm that we installed
in central Beijing,
in an underutilized
underground parking structure
to grow vegetables for the nearby hotels
under utilized infrastructure
is not simply limited to large scale
civil engineering projects.
and they can also include smaller spaces
like idle restaurant corners.
this is an example of a farm
that we installed directly
into the partition of a hotel entrance
in order to grow fresh herbs
and microgreens on site for the chefs.
honestly, if you look around,
you will find
under utilized space everywhere,
under around an inside
of urban urban developments.
this is a farm that we installed
into an empty office corner
to grow fresh vegetables
for the employees in nearby cafes.
I get to be a part
of all these cool projects,
and and working in the agriculture industry
to improve access and affordability,
to fresh and nutritious produce.
hopefully soon by anyone,
anywhere has been the greatest joy,
and also the most humbling
and intellectually challenging thing
I've ever done.
And now that I've convinced you
that agriculture can be quite sexy.
you will be surprised
and shocked to know
that I still have trouble
fully articulating
how and why I decided to work
or and continue to work
in the agricultural industry.
but a couple years ago,
I found a rather unique answer
hiding in plane slight you see?
I read an article
about how your name particularly your last name
can have a strong influence
on everything from your personality
to your professional career.
this is my Japanese last name.
hold up.
and the characters
translate literally into small farm.
thank you.